



# **Mahdi Rahman**

Sr. Product Designer/Design System Manager | Helsinki, Finland

With over twelve years in digital product design, I've worked across B2B and B2C platforms in telecommunications, healthcare, classified ads, E-commerce, and intranet domains. My experience spans the entire design process, from problem identification to solution development, emphasizing inclusivity and collaboration with product managers and developers. I prioritize data-driven transparency to ensure logical and understandable design decisions.

A key aspect of my approach is building a feedback loop with end-users, grounding product evolution in real data. This commitment to iterative improvement has been central to my career.

In my role leading the Design System and engineering team for a B2C product with over 35 million users, I navigated the complexities of documenting and systematizing design within a diverse team of UX designers, researchers, and developers. This experience highlighted the importance of a systematic approach and clear documentation in achieving team success and product excellence.

UX Design Product Design Design System Design Thinking

UX Research UI Design Prototype User-Flow Research Planning

Usability Test Data/Metric Driven Design Interaction Design

in ()

# **Experiences**

## Happeo

#### Sr. Product Designer/Design System Manager {Apr 2022 - Present}

- $^{\circ}$  Successfully initiated the mobile app design process, identifying key problems, conducting extensive user research, implementing solutions, and establishing a scalable feedback loop with end-users.
- $^{\circ}$  Developed, managed, and maintained the Happeo design system (Vesa), aligning it with product scaling and including a strategic phased integration roadmap.
- $_{\circ}$  Created research method templates for use by the product team, enhancing our research capabilities.
- $^\circ$  Designed the platform's advanced analytics section, incorporating sophisticated filters and data visualization tools.
- $_{\circ}$  Designed the platform's AI search experience providing services from LLM(PaLM 2), Vector and Semantic search engine and integration of RAG evaluator

#### Divar

#### **UX Engineering Chapter Leader** {Feb 2020 - Apr 2022}

 Leading the UXE chapter (included 3 UX designers, 1 Researcher, and 4 engineers), I've guided the creation and upkeep of the <u>SONNAT design system</u> for Divar, Iran's leading classified ads platform with 35 million monthly active users.

## **UX Engineer** {Feb 2019 - Feb 2020}

- Led the redesign of Divar's platform website and PWA, leveraging user behavior data and usability testing to establish solid design foundations and navigation strategies.
- $_{\circ}$  Collaborated with a team of more than 10 front-end developers(Android, Android TV, iOS, and web/PWA) to ensure the precise implementation of our progressive design system.
- $^{\circ}$  Initiated and managed the recruitment and evaluation of design engineers, founding the first UXE team in Iran.

#### Praxo Health Information

```
Co-Founder | Product Designer {Feb 2017 - May 2019}
```

In 2017, I co-founded Praxo, a web-based platform for health records and communication between physicians and medical professionals. I oversaw product design, UX research, pro-user interviews, NPS/SUS evaluations, and front-end development using React and React Native.

#### Behineh Pardazan Rizmoj Sanat

```
UX Designer | UI Developer {Apr 2013 - Jan 2017}
```

I was a UI developer and UX designer at an innovative telecom company in Iran, creating components and interfaces for VSR IFF systems, online flight tracking, and commercial radar systems.

#### Iranian TV Channel

```
Graphic Designer | UX Designer {Jan 2012 - Apr 2013}
```

# Ortod Advertising Agency

Graphic Designer | Printing Supervisor {Aug 2010 - Jan 2012}

## Skills

## Softwares {Design}

Figma, Sketch App, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effect, Cinema 4D(basics), ProtoPie

# **Tools** {Research & Discovery}

Dovetail, Typeform, Optimal Workshop, UX Sort, Maze, Miro, FigJam, ProductBoard, Pendo, GA, Storybook/Chromatic, Zeroheight

# Programming & Languages {Development}

HTML, CSS, JS, React JS, QT, Python(basics)

## Product Design & Design Engineering {Bridge skill-set}

- Design system management and documentation ... UI Development in production level
- ر. Interface design / Interaction design
- ∘ UX design, usability testing and A/B testing ∘ Qualitative and Quantitative Research
- Problem Discovery and scope definition
- Prototyping and UI implementation
- Performance wise design

- Design technology and development validation
- Design tokens
- Digital wellbeing and accessibility
- Define Detailed scenario for OA team

#### Websites

**SONNAT Design System** {Design system documentation}

SONNAT Design System {Design system developer tools, React components & resources}

Paskoocheh {My leading experience in a 3D modeling/three.js hackathon project}

## **Publication**

<u>Design Engineering Hand Book</u> {My translation of Design Better handbook}

#### Language

Persian {Native} English (Fluent)

#### Education

## B.SC. Chemistry Engineering, Oil Process Design {2008}

Babol Noshirvani university of technology | Babol, Iran

#### Side Courses

# Philosophy of Art {2015}

Allameh Tabataba'i University